# **Treasury Director**

TREASURY & CORPORATE FINANCE & REPORTING & LIQUIDITY MANAGEMENT & FINANCIAL RISK MANAGEMENT & TREASURY CENTRALISATION AND OPTIMISATION & CAPITAL MARKETS & BANKING & TRADING & FINANCIAL DERIVATIVES & BLOCKCHAIN AND NEW TECHNOLOGY ENTHUSIAST & PYTHON

Treasury manager for last 9 years. Extensive experience in organizing financing, hedging financial risks, including foreign exchange and interest rate. Cash forecasting and liquidity management for the group, implementation of the cash-pool and intercompany bonds. Centralisation of treasury function within international Orange group and participation in optimization projects (improved cash flow, lower number of reports across finance organisation). Projects required cooperation with financial institutions (banks and rating agencies). Developed programing tools (in Python) to optimize Treasury workflow.

**Strong apprenticeship in banking environment.** Experience and knowledge in the sphere of banking products and financial instruments. Cooperation with market regulators (Central bank, Polish Financial Supervision Authority, Ministry of Finance). Currency and interest rate arbitrage, liquidity management of the bank, building hedging solutions for bank's customers, analysis of financial markets.

### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE IN

- ✓ Team management
- ✓ Budgeting, forecasting, financial modelling
- ✓ Supervision of the operation, and updates of front office system KTP
- ✓ ISDA negotiations
- ✓ Hedge accounting, IFRS
- ✓ SOX

#### SELECTED PROFESSIONAL ACHIEVEMENTS

• Centralization and optimization of Treasury Orange Group and the implementation of cross border cash-pool • Implementation of reporting financial derivatives under the provisions of EMIR in Orange Poland • Optimization of reporting the finance function in Orange Poland • Intragroup financing from Orange France and with subsidiaries • Leader of turnover on local market FOREX • Introduction of new financial broker on the Polish market •

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Orange Poland, Financing and Treasury, Warsaw

July 2011 – ongoing

# **Treasury Director**

- Securing financial risk in Orange group. Currency and interest rate hedging.
- Group liquidity management. Implemented cross-border cash-pool, intercompany bonds.
- Cooperation with financial institutions (banks, credit rating agencies).
- ISDA business negotiations, SOX Treasury supervision.
- Implemented EMIR regulations in Orange.
- Financing projects including intercompany debt and back up financing.
- Change management, process optimization in Treasury and centralization of finance function in a group of Orange.
- Budgeting and management of financial costs.
- Maintaining relationships within the Orange Group and its subsidiaries.
- Supervision and upgrade of front office system (Kondor Trade Processing) and its cost optimization.
- Other projects: shares buy back, guarantees, factoring, leasing, hedging of Management Incentive Program with equity options.
- Author of the Orange coin project development of cryptocurrency as marketing tool.

### FX Senior Dealer - head of FX desk

- Market maker for PLN currency crosses.
- Cooperation with the Ministry of Finance.
- Preparation of hedging ideas and solutions for bank's customers with currency risk exposure.
- Running technical and fundamental analysis for sales desk.
- Cooperation within the CEEMEA Hub.
- Highest FX turnover on local market in Poland 2001 2009 (according to Reuters).

### Cantor Fitzgerald International, EM Desk, London

September 2001 – May 2002

### **Head of CE4 Fixed Income Desk**

- Introduction to the Polish market new financial broker.
- Maintaining relations with Polish customers.
- Strategy and team management.

## DZ Bank (Poland) Warsaw, Treasury, Warsaw

September 2000 - August 2001

#### **Senior Fixed Income Dealer**

- Treasury securities interbank trading.
- Implementation and procedures for new products: FRA, IRS.
- Achieved 20% of average turnover at primary treasury auctions.

# Bank Handlowy w Warszawie SA, Treasury, Warsaw

April 1996 – September 2000

#### **Senior Fixed Income Dealer**

- Treasury and commercial paper trading.
- Marketing of treasury securities among foreign investors.
- EUROMONEY 1999: Best Fixed Income House in Emerging Markets.
- Highest turnover of Polish treasuries in 1998 2000.

#### **EDUCATION**

Kozminski University, MBA program

June 2016

• The Private University of Social, Computer and Medical Sciences, Warsaw Finance and Accounting (master thesis: Derivatives and its development in Poland)

June 1996

### SELECTED TRAINING AND ACTIVITIES

CodersLab Bootcamp (Warsaw 2018), Being a line manager (Paris 2017), Pursuing CIMA; Situational Leadership SLII, Motivation and engagement (Warsaw 2014); Change management (Warsaw 2013); Cash-pooling (Warsaw 2012); Options Volatility Trading, (New York 2008); Citibank Bucharest – trading team rebuilding (Bucharest 2007); Fundamentals of Pricing and Trading Options, (London 2006); Corporate Finance, (Warsaw 2003); Kondor+implementation in Bank Handlowy w Warszawie SA, London Branch (London 1999).

### **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

Languages: English (fluent, daily use in business environment), German (basic), Italian (basic). Analytical, accountable, team player, strong organizational skills, ability to build and manage team, in depth knowledge of economics and financial markets, ability to work under time pressure and in dynamic environment.

Interests: blockchain, Python, web development, travelling, reading, cinema, basketball.